Abraham: So, let’s start by
having a recap on some of the
best methods for maintaining
security to refresh your memory.
Businesses large and small can use
different methods to maintain cyber
security to keep their data safe online.
These can give a basic level of
security against the most common risks.
Intrusion detectors can be used to
monitor a system and any unusual activity.
Also raising awareness of all
employees and their role in
keeping a business cyber secure.
As we have mentioned previously, using
strong passwords such as those using a
combination of capital and lower-case
letters, numbers, and symbols and multi
factor authentication are important
and having a password policy can help
staff follow best security practice.
Controlling access to data by
making sure that individuals only
have access to data and services
for which they are authorised.
This may involve physical restrictions
to certain premises or application
controls limiting access to networks
which we covered in the last unit.
Firewalls are effective gatekeepers
and a major barrier to cyber threats,
software and firmware updates
should always be kept up with.
Having suitable anti-malware software
installed and regularly updated is
essential to protect your system.
Ensure that data is consistently backed
up using any protected back up devices,
so that if a system is hacked or corrupted
the information can be retrieved.
Remember make sure that your system
is not vulnerable to the risk of cyber
security attack as much as you can, by
being aware of how cyber secure you are.